[Music]
Hello.
Hi Joe. Hi Joe. Hello. Happy New Year.
Suppose.
What's it like knowing that this is the
last week of the year? I mean, what are
the feelings going into that as opposed
to maybe other game weeks?
Yeah, obviously disappointing, but
got one one chance to
go out and play well and play hard and
show what you got.
Joe, if you could think big picture, I
know it's difficult at times on a
Wednesday like this to think about your
career. You're almost 6 years down now.
What you've done so far versus what's
still ahead? What What do you still want
to accomplish? What do you think still
needs to be done for you to accomplish
the best of the best?
Obviously, you want to win a Super Bowl.
You want to win MVPs.
You want to be in the playoffs every
every year, but
[Music]
my goals at this point are just going
out and playing as
good as I can and continuing to improve,
finding ways to
continue to be great and
continue to to find self-improvement.
How how many times will you have
conversations with not just coaching
staff, but top of the organization going
into the off season about certain things
that need to change or or grow or
improve to make this team better? Yeah,
I don't know. We'll see. We'll see how
it goes. Is that something you you try
to
go after those conversations? I mean, as
much as you can.
We have great line of communication.
Me, Duke,
Katie Troy, Mr. Brown, Zach. You know,
it's
We have great communication.
Is it kind of been
What's it been like kind of not being
able to have as much control as you
would maybe like
with other parts of the team? It sounds
like you're like, I can control what I
can. Has that been a bit of a challenge
as you kind of gotten older in your
career?
I wouldn't say that. I think
I'm not sure I would
say
agree with the first part of your
statement.
I'm not sure
I want I want to be a quarterback. I
don't want to
I don't want to work in the front
office. I don't want to be
scouting
guys in the off season.
I want to do what I do and I want to do
it at a high level and I have.
And I'm going to continue to find
more and more ways that I can
help myself get better, help the team
get better, and put ourselves in good
positions. All right, so a better way to
ask that would have been, has it been
Have you just been trying to focus on
everything you can control and and just
kind of say, you know what, this is kind
of what I can deal with. Let me try to
handle that as best I can. Has that been
a bigger bigger point of emphasis this
year for you, do you think? Yeah, I
would say that's fair. I think
my job is to
number one,
play as well as I can.
Number two, continue to improve.
And number three, be the conduit between
coaching staff, front office, and the
locker room.
Relay
feelings that players have.
Relay sentiments in the locker room
because, you know, coaches and front
office, they're not down there every day
and they don't understand
a lot of the things that
go on in the locker room. And so, I
think you know, as quarterback, your job
is to
relay some of those things. How
important is it for for this franchise
this off season to make whatever the
moves are, but the necessary moves, so a
year from now we're not saying out loud
the final piece. Yeah, we want to we
want to be competing for championships
every every year. We don't want to be in
a spot that we're in now. So,
something's got to change, whether
um players that we have continuing to
improve and get better and playing
championship caliber football or
bringing guys in that that will or
whatever it may be, obviously something
has to.
Joe,
I don't know how much college football
you watch over, you know, 23, 24. I ask
this because, you know, Shedeur Sanders
going to be starting for Cleveland on
Sunday. Did Did you get a chance to
watch him? And if so, what do you think
of his game and also kind of how he's
handled the unusual spotlight that's
kind of come with him?
Yeah, I really enjoyed watching him in
college. I thought he made a lot of
plays.
I thought he could throw it.
And then obviously,
given who his dad is, he
he knows how to handle the
media, knows how to handle the
spotlight.
Certainly been under more of a
microscope than any other
What did he get drafted fourth round?
Yes. Fifth round. Certainly under the
microscope more than any other fifth
round pick that's ever been
in the history of football.
And
every clip that I see,
you know, he seems to be handling it
well, says most of the right things
in the media.
He just
is who he is. He's himself. That's what
you want out of a a football player. So,
he seems to be handling it the right
way. Has he Has he ever come up in
conversations that you and Flacco have
had at any point considering, you know,
Flacco was with him, you know, in
Cleveland up until he came here? Yeah,
you talk about a lot of different
players across the league.
And that's typically
you know, you get a new guy, you figure
out
he was with this guy I was with or he
was with this guy. I wonder what he
thought about about him.
That's kind of you know, the initial
conversations that you have with new
guys that come into the locker room and
try to find some common ground in that
way. Is there anything between
the conversations you've had with Joe
about Shedeur that you could share or
anything like that or
Keep that between Keep that in the
locker room. Yes, sir.
You picked You picked Joe's brain at all
on the Cleveland defense? Kind of a rare
opportunity to get a guy who's
Um no, not really.
They they do what they do for the most
part. They're pretty simple on defense.
That certainly doesn't mean that
they don't provide
problematic looks and
disguises.
And certainly doesn't mean that they're
not good on defense. They're, in my
opinion, the best defense in football.
So,
it's certainly going to be a challenge
with the
number one, the
players that they have. Number two, the
coach that they have understands
the strengths and weaknesses of his
players and puts them in good positions.
Is there anything that Flacco is that
you've taken
You've had more than half of the wins in
your
Anything maybe you've
gleaned from him? Yeah, there's
certainly
you know, I take things from from a lot
of different people across the league
and
certainly when you get a chance to
sit back and watch somebody else go have
success the way that he did, you um and
a style that
I don't play in that not a ton of people
do play in the league anymore.
You know, you certainly take some things
from
from watching that and you know, apply
to yourself. Anything you can share?
Not that I can share.
Throughout your career, whenever you
guys play the Browns, it comes up about
Myles Garrett. He's going for the sack
record on Sunday.
And I know you've answered this before,
but what is it that makes it so
difficult that he's so different, Myles
Garrett? What about him?
He's more athletic than everybody else
on the field.
He's bigger, stronger than everybody
else.
He has a mindset that
he's not too high or too low at any
point, which is pretty
unique for for a defensive lineman. I
think he's probably got a unique mindset
as far as that position goes, but it's
one that you can appreciate.
Um he's a guy that I've
kind of gotten to know over the years
and, you know, I like him as a person.
And uh he takes his job very seriously
and
he's a guy I have a lot of respect for.
Your thoughts on him potentially sacking
you for the record?
He's got me a lot.
He's got me a lot. Joe, you've talked
about wanting to have a lot more fun in
recent weeks. Are you having fun right
now even though this season has been a
losing season? These last couple of
weeks scoring a lot, has that been fun
for you?
I have had fun. I think
um
I have fun playing football.
It's uh
certainly difficult when you can't.
And you know, I had fun last year, too.
Certainly frustrating at times. That's
life in the NFL. That's life of playing
sports and that's
you know, why you play it at the
beginning. You feel
emotions that you don't feel in other
parts of your life. Highs, lows,
all of the above, everything in between.
That's why people fall in love with
sports. Fans feel it.
We feel it. Coaches feel it. Everybody
feels it. And uh
that's why you fall in love with it from
a young age and that's personally why I
do it.
How big would it be for this offense to
continue what you've done over the past
couple of weeks against that defense?
Yeah, we want to go out and play well.
Obviously, we
um
anytime you step out there, you want to
execute the plan at a high level and
put points up and
play well, but
anytime you play divisional opponent,
the stakes are raised a little bit.
Given Given what you said a few years
ago about the window being your whole
career, how do you kind of square that
with how the last few seasons have gone
given what you expect to accomplish at
the end of each year?
Yeah, I feel confident every time I step
foot on the field that
you know, we have a great chance to win.
And
you know, really this year,
you know, I've played I've played
however many games and
we've won more than we've lost and I
feel good about that.
Um
All I can do is
go out and
when I'm out on the field, try to play
well, try to win, and
go from there.
With the calendar with the calendar year
ending today, what's your New Year's
resolution? Be happy.
Yeah, so you know, obviously with Miles,
you know, one sack away from the record,
how I obviously I know you and the
entire team have a lot of respect for
him. How do you How do you weigh, you
know, trying to not let him not
necessarily let him have the record
against you versus not having so much
focus beyond him that it takes away from
what you're trying to do it trying to do
as far as winning the game? Yeah, I'm
certainly
not going to overcompensate either way.
I'm not going to
go out of my way to not let him get the
record, and I'm not going to go out of
my way to to let him get the record
either. I'm going to go and play
football. There's going to be
situations that a sack is the best of
the bad
outcomes of that play, and maybe I take
one. And there's going to be other
situations that I'm about to get sacked,
and
I need to throw it away in that
situation. It's such a such a
situational game
that
um
I don't think you can go in thinking one
way or the other. Every play is so
different. Did you expect this to be
such a rebuilding year that it that it
ended up turning out to be? Like at the
beginning of the year, did you expect
y'all to be kind of the rebuilding mode
that y'all ended up finding yourself in
middle of the season?
>> No, every every year we go in, I feel
confident in who we are, what we have,
and
the dialogues of the season.
When you
get injured and can't impact that, it
certainly hurts.
And so, uh you know, going forward, I'm
just going to try to
control what I can control. Is it hard
not to go into
reflection mode
right now, or is it easy to stay locked
in on on the Browns, knowing that it's
the final game of the season?
It's kind of all all the above.
Obviously, you're reflecting on the year
the season is about to end, but I think
you can
I think the
professionals can simultaneously reflect
on everything that has happened before.
And number one, you have to in order to
get better. You have to reflect on all
the things that worked and didn't work
work for
the previous 16 games, and
you can simultaneously do that and focus
on the task at hand and the game plan
and what you need to do to win on
Sunday.
How much better prepared do you think
your offensive line is compared to week
one for that Miles Garrett challenge?
>> Yeah, I think they're playing
exponentially better than they were at
the time. And I I know they're excited
excited about the challenge. I know
you know, their front is
tough to deal with, starting with him,
but they have a lot of other guys too
that
can be very challenging to to handle up
front. So,
I know they're excited for it. Given the
style that you guys are playing, do you
think you know, your tackles uh do you
think your tackles are judged maybe
differently maybe cuz, you know, you
guys play
play a style not a lot of teams do. How
do you How do you think they fared?
Yeah, I think this is the
This is the most comfortable I've felt
back there
since I've been in the league. I think
I think we've also done a better job
this year of mixing in
different looks, different personnels,
and and running the ball in different
situations, and I think that has
helped those guys up front and helped us
as an offense, too.
You know, obviously, we're we're built
in the
on the outside and the explosive pass
game, but I think we've taken a step
this year as far as
being a physical downhill run team. You
mentioned the different looks under
center than you've been in the past.
I've always been comfortable in
whatever's asked
asked of me for that play.
You mentioned the different looks could
be part of the reason, but at why in
your opinion otherwise has the offensive
line gotten so much better throughout
the season this year? Well, you you
should get better throughout the season,
I think.
If you're not getting better throughout
the season, then it's one of two things.
Either
you have a lot of injuries throughout
the year, and those guys don't have a
ton of time together, or
you don't have the the right guys. Cuz
if you're not getting better throughout
the season and you have all the same
guys out there, then those guys aren't
talking through technique, talking
through different looks, talking through
how they're going to help each other in
in all these different situations that
pop up throughout the game. And so,
any
any good player is going to
consistently improve game to game, week
to week. So, then couldn't you make the
same argument then for the a defensive
line that they should be getting better
throughout the season? Like do you think
the offensive line has the advantage as
the season goes on?
I've always felt like it's easier to
play
defenses at the end of the year
mainly because
of injuries and different guys coming in
and out of lineup. The very very rarely
do you play a defense in November,
December, January that has all the same
guys starting as they did August,
September, and whatnot.
There was a screenshot uh not saying
change up your but the screenshot of you
coughing on the sidelines that's uh made
the rounds. Can you give a little more
context on to what exactly was I'm just
curious. Like what were y'all talking
about on the sideline that prompted
that?
>> We were talking about how it feels to be
uh under a pile Okay. Yeah. So, was
somebody coughing underneath the pile?
It was It was more of a guttural yell
kind of thing.
Who was was it you? Did you get to the
bottom of who was yelling? It was Ted.
It's common for just about everybody
under the pile. Last couple weeks, Ted
is Ted's been the guy. Yeah.
Ted brought you
a spread. You asked for a waffle, he
brought you a spread. You reacted to it.
What How much did he bring? Too much.
Too many things. I I I appreciate it,
but
I didn't need I didn't need six
six things. I just needed one little
snack, and then I was going to be good
to go.
Yeah, this might be a hard one to
answer. I'll try not to ask it in a
clumsy way, but we have a reporter
working on a story with a family who
lost a 13-year-old boy unexpectedly in
the last couple of weeks.
Lifelong Bengals fan, fan of you and
Ja'Marr and all the stars on this team,
and they kind of vowed to go to every
Bengals home game when they can going
forward. I guess the question is, there
people going through hard times this
time of year that are also diehard
Bengals fans.
How do you receive that? How aware are
you of that? That, you know, you having
a big highlight or a big play when
they're there and and also mourning is
meaningful for them.
Yeah, I take a lot of pride in the fact
that
what I do brings people together and
brings happiness and
um
you know, for me personally, brings my
family and friends together, gives us a
chance to
come to the games, interact, gives my
friends, high school coaches a chance to
get together and come and see me play. I
take a lot of pride in that. Uh
And then, obviously, not just my family,
but
Bengals fans across the world, you know,
I hope that I I and we can bring
people together at the end of the day.
That's what sports does.
That's another reason why people love
it.
You You unites people. It
find You find common ground with
people that you otherwise wouldn't, and
then
it builds relationships and love and all
of those things. And so, you know, I
take a lot of pride in that. That's why,
you know, I fight so hard to be on the
field and fight so hard to to go and
play well because I know that it means a
lot to a lot of people.
Thanks, Joe.
Thanks, Joe. Thanks, Joe.
[Music]